flybuys.com.au 2006-06-15

# Welcome to FlyBuys : Information

| 

|  

FlyBuys is changing the FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy. This notice describes the changes that are being made. These changes will come into effect on 1 January 2006. You can call us on 13 1116, if you would like a full copy of the amended FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy.

**What are the changes?**

There are four key changes to the FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy. In summary, from 1 January 2006:

  * FlyBuys will be allowed to disclose your personal information (including your name) to Coles Myer Ltd. (and its group companies) and the National Australia Bank Limited (and its group companies), as owners of the FlyBuys program.
  * Coles Myer Ltd (and its group companies) and the National Australia Bank Limited (and its group companies) will be allowed to collect your name and other personal information from FlyBuys. They may use and disclose that personal information within their corporate groups (and to their service providers) for marketing, planning, product development, research, FlyBuys account reconciliation and other related purposes (including to send you direct marketing information).
  * If you nominate an additional cardholder or provide personal information to FlyBuys about another person (for example, a family member), you will have to make sure that the person has:
    * read and understood the FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy; and
    * agreed to their personal information being collected, used and disclosed in accordance with the FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy.
  * Unless you instruct us otherwise, we will be able to use your electronic addresses (including your e-mail address and mobile phone number for receiving SMS), to the extent that you have provided them, to let you know about upgrades to our online services (such as Reward Redemption) and to send you FlyBuys program and marketing communications.

The FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy has also been updated to mention some privacy issues regarding use of the FlyBuys website and suggest what to do if you are concerned about cookies being placed on your computer when you use the FlyBuys website.

There are also some other minor changes being made. These include changes to:

  * update the list of types of personal information that may be held on the FlyBuys database;
  * include some definitions of words used in the FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy; and 
  * give you details on how to unsubscribe from the FlyBuys email database if you do not want to receive e-mails from FlyBuys.

go to top

**What do I need to do?**

If you are happy with these changes you do not need to do anything. The changes will come into effect automatically. 

If you do not wish to be bound by these changes, you can withdraw from FlyBuys. You can do this by writing to us at: Loyalty Pacific Pty Ltd, PO Box 12125, A' Beckett Street, Melbourne, VIC 8006.

You can, at any time, tell us not to disclose your name to Coles Myer Ltd (and its group companies) or National Australia Bank Limited (and its group companies). You can do this by writing to us or by calling 13 1116.

go to top

**What do I need to do if there are any additional cardholders?**

If you have previously nominated an additional cardholder or provided personal information to FlyBuys about a family member or any other person, you should give that person a copy of this notice and make sure that they understand the notice and that they can tell us not to disclose their name to Coles Myer Ltd. (and its group companies) or National Australia Bank Limited (and its group companies) by calling 13 1116. If that person is under 18 years of age, please make sure that a parent or guardian reads this notice on their behalf.

**Where can I get a full copy of the amended FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy?**

A full copy of the amended FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy can be viewed on our website at [www.flybuys.com.au](http://www.flybuys.com.au/). 

You can also call us on 13 1116 if you would like us to send you a full copy of the amended FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy.

go to top

## How we respect your privacy.

**Introduction**

At FlyBuys, we respect the privacy of your personal information in our care. This commitment is demonstrated in our Policy on Information Privacy.

Members have the right to opt out of mailings other than their Points Summary. They can access their personal information by writing to FlyBuys at the address indicated below.

  1. **Members' Rights**

Loyalty Pacific Pty Ltd as manager of the FlyBuys program respects and upholds the rights of members to privacy protection. The provisions of this Policy are evidence of Loyalty Pacific Pty Ltd's commitment to that protection. This Policy applies to all personal information held in the FlyBuys database. Refer section 5 of the FlyBuys Terms and Conditions. Words and phrases defined in the FlyBuys Terms and Conditions have the same meaning when used in this Policy. In this Policy "CML Group Entities" means Coles Myer Ltd. (ABN 11 004 089 936) and its related bodies corporate and "NAB Group Entities" means National Australia Bank Limited ABN 12 004 044 937 and its related bodies corporate including MLC Ltd and Custom Service Leasing Limited (trading as Custom Fleet).

go to top

  2. **Information - Collection**

**2.1** FlyBuys will, at all times, collect personal information in a fair and lawful manner.

**2.2** The FlyBuys database may comprise any of the following personal information, held by FlyBuys: 

    * name, address(es) & telephone number(s) 
    * electronic addresses
    * gender
    * date of birth
    * employment status
    * information about credit cards linked to FlyBuys
    * transaction details associated with the earning of FlyBuys points 
    * points earned and rewards provided 
    * names, genders and dates of birth of additional cardholders
    * ages of other family members. 

Members' signatures/authorities are also collected by FlyBuys.

**2.3** If you are a FlyBuys member or simply inquiring about our online services such as Rewards Redemption, we may use your electronic addresses (such as your email address or mobile phone number for receiving SMS) to advise you of any upgrades or changes to these services.

We may also use your electronic addresses to send you from time to time various FlyBuys program and marketing communications.

If we send you an electronic message for a commercial purpose, we will give you the option of not receiving further communications of this nature.

go to top

  3. **Information - Purpose & Usage**   
**3.1** Personal information including your electronic addresses will be used for two primary purposes. First, it will be used to ensure the proper functioning of the FlyBuys program. Secondly, and subject to the restrictions set out in paragraph 3.3, it will be used by FlyBuys and the participating retailers for marketing, planning, product development, research, FlyBuys account administration and fraud and crime prevention and investigation.

**3.2** FlyBuys will not use or disclose or permit the use or disclosure of personal information that could be used to identify an individual member in any circumstances except: 

    1. to ensure the proper functioning of the FlyBuys program in relation to the member in question (for example, to confirm membership and acceptance of the Terms and Conditions, to communicate points earned, to seek the member's views on the operation of the FlyBuys program in order to improve member service, to ensure the integrity of points processing by participating retailers, to communicate promotional offers and special events and to identify the member when rewards are made) and for these purposes personal information will only be disclosed to FlyBuys or a service provider retained by FlyBuys under conditions of confidentiality; 
    2. where the personal information is to be used by CML Group Entities or NAB Group Entities for the purposes described in clause 3.3;
    3. otherwise, where the personal information is to be used by a participating retailer for marketing, planning, product development and research and where
      1. the personal information does not include the name of the member; and 
      2. the participating retailer is bound by a confidentiality agreement with FlyBuys under which the personal information may not be used for mailing purposes or in any other way to make contact with the member; 
    4. when FlyBuys is required or authorised by law to disclose the personal information;
    5. for fraud and crime prevention and investigation; or 
    6. when the member specifically consents in writing to the use or disclosure. 

Examples of the service providers referred to in paragraph 3.2(a) are data processing and data analysis agents, printing contractors and the FlyBuys Customer Service Centre. Information will only be provided to these agents to the extent necessary to enable them to undertake their contracted roles in the operation of the FlyBuys program.

**3.3** CML Group Entities and NAB Group Entities may collect the member's name and other personal information from FlyBuys for marketing, planning, product development, research, FlyBuys account reconciliation, fraud and crime prevention and investigation and other related purposes. To perform these activities CML Group Entities and NAB Group Entities may share your personal information with: 
    * if the entity is a CML Group Entity, other CML Group Entities and if the entity is a NAB Group Entity, other NAB Group Entities;
    * service providers such as data processing and data analysis agents, printing contractors, customer service organisations, call centres, professional advisers, auditors, delivery companies and mailing organisations; and
    * other organisations as required or authorised by law, for example, to government or regulatory bodies for the prevention or detection of unlawful activities.
**3.4** FlyBuys undertakes to give proper and responsible consideration to privacy issues associated with the introduction of new marketing devices or technology. 

**3.5** On termination of membership, the member's contact details will be noted as closed, and after twelve months of non-card usage such contact details will be deleted from the FlyBuys database and the member's point balance cancelled. 

go to top

  4. **Members' Right to Opt Out**

**4.1** From time to time, promotional offers and special events will be communicated to members by FlyBuys other than through Points Summary mailings. Members have the right to opt out of these additional communications and can do so by requesting this in writing to FlyBuys. 

**4.2** Members can tell FlyBuys not to disclose their name to CML Group Entities and NAB Group Entities. Members can make this request by writing to FlyBuys or calling 13 1116. 

**4.3** To unsubscribe from the FlyBuys email database, please send an email to [**internet.flybuys@flybuys.com.au**](mailto:flybuys@flybuys.com.au) with "UNSUBSCRIBE" typed into the body of the email. For technical reasons you will not receive a notice when you unsubscribe from this list. 

go to top

  5. **Security Safeguards**

**5.1** FlyBuys undertakes to take reasonable steps to ensure that member information is secure from any unauthorised access or disclosure. 

**5.2** FlyBuys assumes no responsibility for the information practices of third-party websites where a user is able to access their websites through the FlyBuys website, and encourages users to review each website's privacy policy before disclosing any personally identifying information.

go to top

  6. **Your privacy on the FlyBuys website**   
Cookies may be used on some areas of our website. A cookie is a small file placed on a user's hard drive which tracks website navigation. For example, a cookie can be used to store registration information so that a user does not need to re-enter it on subsequent visits. 

If you are concerned about cookies, most browsers have an option which permits users to refuse a cookie. A user can refuse a cookie and still fully navigate our website.

In order to collect user statistics we may anonymously log information, and identify categories of users by items such as domains and browser types.

go to top

  7. **Openness**

**7.1** Information about privacy and the FlyBuys program will be made available at or prior to application for membership. A current version of the FlyBuys Policy on Information Privacy is available at the FlyBuys website and on request by calling 13 1116. 

**7.2** Members may request access to their personal information on the FlyBuys database. Such requests must be in writing to FlyBuys. A fee for reasonable costs incurred may be charged in responding to these written requests, such fee being made known to the member before it is incurred. 

**7.3** Members may request access to their personal information held by CML Group Entities and NAB Group Entities by contacting those organisations directly. 

**7.4** Members have the right to update any incorrect personal information.

go to top

  8. **Information about additional cardholders and other persons**

Members that nominate an additional cardholder or provide personal information about a family member or any other individual must first ensure that the individual concerned: 

    * has seen this Policy on Information Privacy and understood its contents; and 

has separately agreed to their personal information being collected, used and disclosed in accordance with this Policy on Information Privacy. 

    * If the individual is under 18 years of age and does not have sufficient maturity and intelligence to understand this Policy on Information Privacy, the primary cardholder must ensure that the individuals parent or guardian agrees to this Policy on Information Privacy on the individuals behalf. 

go to top

  9. **Accountability**

**9.1** FlyBuys will conduct an annual review to ensure observance of this Policy. This will include a review by external auditors as part of their annual audit. A copy of the auditors' conclusions will be made available to members on written request. 

**9.2** Day to day responsibility for the implementation of this Policy rests with the Finance & Administration Manager, Loyalty Pacific, to whom all correspondence should be addressed. (FlyBuys, PO Box 12125, A'Beckett Street Melbourne VIC 8006, or any other address we may tell you from time to time.) 

go to top

---|---
